My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him.
أُجبر طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلص جسده
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
،رغم أنّي أصبحت أصغر !لا يزال عقل عقل متحرٍّ عظيم
Today's case involves a June bride dressed in white!
تتمحور قضيّة اليوم حول عروس يونيو !مكسوّة بالبياض تدنّسها الدماء
Even with her happiness about to crumble, there's always only one truth!
،حتى بينما توشك سعادتها على الانهيار !الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
The June Bride Murder Case.
جريمة قتل عروس يونيو
Today, a middle school teacher that Ran and I had is getting married.
اليوم حفل زفاف لمعلّمةٍ كانت لي وران في المدرسة المتوسطة
But I'm definitely not here for her sake.
مع ذلك لم آت هنا لتهنئتها بالتحديد
I just wanted to see the wacko who's marrying her.
أردتُ رؤية غريب الأطوار الذي سيتزوّجها وحسب
Matsumoto-sensei... I haven't seen her since we graduated!
ماتسوموتو سينسي... لم أرها مُذ تخرّجنا
Maybe we'll get to hear her amazing singing voice at the reception!
ربما سنسمع غناءها الجميل مُجدداً في الحفل
Oh yeah, what about you-know-who?
بالمناسبة، ماذا عنه؟
You know, the kid who would always get yelled at
ذاك الذي كانت سينسي توبّخه دوماً
for being off key in Matsumoto-sensei's music class...
لانحرافه عن النغم في درس الموسيقى
I called him but he said wouldn't go even if his life depended on it.
"!اتّصلتُ به لكنه قال "من قد يذهب لذاك الزفاف؟
So you brought this kid with you instead of Mr. Tone-Deaf?
فأحضرتِ هذا الفتى بدلاً من ميّت النغم ذاك؟
Yep! He insisted on coming!
أجل، أصرّ على القدوم
Excuse me for being tone-deaf!
أعتذر لكوني ميت النغم
That lousy woman did nothing but torture me for three full years!
لم تقم تلك المرأة سوى بتعذيبي لثلاث سنين
Oh! Mori-san and Suzuki-san!
!عجباً، موري-سان وسوزوكي-سان
Well? Does it look good on me?
ما رأيكما؟ أيلائمني؟
Y-You look beautiful!
!تـ-تبدين جميلةً جدّاً
S-She does...
...بـ-بالفعل
"Waiting Room" Aw, Kudo-kun can't make it?
غرفة الانتظار
How I wanted to show off this dress in front of that impertinent brat!
أردتُ الاستعراض بهذا الفستان !أمام ذاك الصبيّ المغرور
She hasn't changed at all on the inside...
لم تتغير في داخلها أبداً
Oh?
ماذا؟
Have we met before, little boy?
هل التقينا قبلاً يا فتى؟
N-No!
!لا
Okay! Look this way, you two!
!حسنٌ، انظرا هنا
We're in charge of the video for today!
!نحن المسؤولتان عن التسجيل اليوم
Make sure the kiss scene is a really great one!
احرصي على أن يكون !مشهد التقبيل ممتازاً
Leave it to me!
!دعي الأمر لي
I bought you your warm lemon tea, Sayuri!
أحضرتُ شاي الليمون الدافئ الذي أردته يا سايوري
Thank you!
!شكراً لك
Come to think of it, she was always drinking lemon tea.
صحيح، كانت تشرب الشاي بالليمون دوماً
Even during class...
...حتى أثناء الدرس
Wait! Your lipstick will come off if you drink it like that.
مهلك، سيزول أحمر شفاهك إن شربتِ هكذا
There you go!
هاك
Thanks.
شكراً
Kazumi... I'm sorry...
كازومي، أنا آسفة
About Toshihiko-san...
بخصوص توشيهيكو-سان
What are you talking about at a time like this?
ما الذي تقولينه في وقتٍ كهذا؟
You better be ready!
!يجدر بك أن تتجهزي
I'm gonna tell everyone at the reception
سأخبر الجميع في الحفل أنّ العريس
that your new hubby used to be my boyfriend!
!كان حبيبي السابق
Kazumi...
...كازومي
Just kidding!
!أمزح فقط
See you in a little bit!
أراكِ لاحقاً
She never stops teasing me...
يا إلهي، لا تكفّ عن مضايقتي
Who was that?
من كانت؟
A bad friend of mine from college.
صديقة سيّئة من أيام الجامعة
I have another can, would one of you like it?
توجد عُلبة أخرى، أيريد أحدكم الشرب؟
I'll take it!
!سآخذها
What do you think you're doing?!
!ماذا تظن أنّك تفعل؟
Ran! Beat this gorilla's brains out!
!ران! ابرحي هذا الغوريلا ضرباً
Oh? If it isn't Ran-kun!
!ماذا؟ ران-كن
Inspector Megure! What are you doing here?
مفتّش ميغوري! ماذا تفعل هنا؟
Who in their right mind would miss their boss's daughter's wedding?
من قد يفوت حفل زفاف ابنة مديره؟
Boss?
مديره؟
That's right. He's the police superintendent and my father!
صحيح، إنّه مفوّض الشرطة وأبي
Your father...?
...أ-أبوك
You can go now.
يمكنكم الذهاب
Yes, sir!
!حاضر
Please forgive us!
!المعذرة
Don't worry about it, you two!
لا مشكلة
It's his fault for looking so scary!
فاللوم على أبي لملامحه المخيفة
Anyway, Sayuri, are you really sure you want to marry him?
بالمناسبة يا سايوري، أأنتِ راضية بذاك الرجل حقاً؟
I have young men with plenty of backbone working for me!
!لديّ كتيبة شبّان أسوياء يعملون لي
Dad! What are you saying at a time like this?!
ما الذي تقوله في وقتٍ كهذا؟
Very well.
هكذا إذاً
Really now! You always have to treat me like a child, don't you?!
يا إلهي، لا تكفّ عن معاملتي كطفلة
You are a child.
أنتِ كذلك
You still drink this sugary rubbish...
...لا تزالين تشربين هذا الشراب السكّري
So what?! I like it!
!وما المشكلة؟ يعجبني
Anyway, how about saying something?!
ما رأيك أن تُدلي برأيك في شيءٍ آخر؟
Look at what your daughter is wearing!
!انظر لفستان ابنتك
You're beautiful. Though not nearly as beautiful as your dead mother.
أنتِ جميلة، رغم ليس بحُسن أمّك المتوفاة
Can't you ever give a normal compliment?!
لا يمكنه الثناء عليّ بشكل طبيعي ولو لمرّة
What beautiful roses!
!يا للورود الجميلة
Thank you, Umemiya-kun.
شكراً لك يا أوميميا-كن
Who's he?
من ذاك الشخص؟
You don't remember? That's Umemiya-san-- he was one year ahead of us.
أنسيتِ؟ إنّه أوميميا-سان الذي كان يسبقنا بسنة
Lemon tea suits you well, Matsumoto-sensei.
يلائمك الشاي بالليمون حقاً يا سينسي
Thank you!
شكراً لك
Today is a real disappointment for me.
اليوم خيبة أمل كبيرة لي
I always believed that only I could ever make you happy.
لطالما رأيتُ أنّي وحدي من بإمكانه منحك السعادة
Umemiya-kun...
...أوميميا-كن
See you.
إلى اللقاء
What a conceited jerk.
يا للوغد المتبجح
No way!
!مُحال
Wasn't there an electronics store near here?
ألم يكن هناك متجر الكترونيات في القرب؟
I'll be back soon!
سأذهب لشراء واحدة
Wait for me!
!انتظريني
Jeez, you'd think to at least check that before leaving the house...
كان عليكما تفقّد ذلك قبل مغادرة المنزل
You look exactly like Kudo Shinichi...
تبدو مطابقاً لكودو شينتشي حقاً
Just looking at your face makes me want to pinch you!
مجرد النظر لوجهك يُشعرني !برغبة في مضايقتك
Hey now!
!أنت
After all, Kudo-kun looked just like my very first boyfriend...
فكان كودو-كن يشبه محبوبي الأوّل
His family ran the neighborhood candy store,
كانت عائلته تدير متجر حلويات في الحيّ
and whenever someone was bullying me, he'd always come to my rescue!
وهبّ لمساعدتي متى كان أحدٌ يزعجني
He would always secretly steal my favorite drink from his own store
كان يسرق شرابي المفضّل من متجرهم
and give it to me...
ويعطيني إيّاه سرّاً دوماً
Warm lemon tea!
شاي ليمون دافئ
Unable to forget those memories, I still drink it all the time.
لا أزال أشربه على الدوام لعجزي عن مفارقة هذه الذكريات
It's like it gives me courage.
أشعر أنّه يمدّني بالشجاعة
So he was the reason I was tormented for three long years?
لذا هو كان سبب عذابي لثلاث سنوات؟
So does he still live there?
أيزال ذاك الفتى يعيش هناك؟
No. One day, he suddenly moved away, and I've never seen him since.
كلا، انتقل فجأةً في أحد الأيام ولم أره بعدها
But there's more to this story...
...لكن هناك تتمة لهذه القصة
Hey, what're you being so shy about? You're the groom!
!ما الذي يخجلك؟ أنتَ العريس
Toshihiko-san!
توشيهيكو-سان
This is just our little secret, okay?
أبقِ هذا الكلام سرّاً بيننا، اتّفقنا؟
Are you still drinking this cheap filth?
لا تزالين تشربين هذا المشروب الرديء؟
Y-Yes...
...أجل
You're the successor to the Takasugi Group!
!أنتَ وريث مجموعة تاكاسوغي
You know him?
تعرفينه يا سونوكو؟
I see him at parties all the time.
أراه في الحفلات دائماً
He's indecisive and undependable,
إنه شخص متردّد وعديم المسؤولية
and people say that the Takasugi family's going to end with him...
...ويُقال أنّ عائلة تاكاسوغي ستنتهي به
Where did that come from all of a sudden?
لمَ فجأةً؟
But she's with him, so I think he'll be all right...
لكنّها معه، لذا أظنّه سيكون بخير
Sorry to interrupt, but it's almost time for the ceremony.
المعذرة، وقت الاحتفال اقترب
Right!
حـ-حسناً
Go on ahead, Toshihiko-san.
يمكنك أن تسبقني يا توشيهيكو-سان
Don't worry, I'll be there soon!
لا تقلق، سألحق بك قريباً
Oh, okay...
حـ-حسناً
So, how's the bride?
كيف كانت العروس إذاً؟
Way to go!
!أنت
What was that sound?!
ما كان ذاك الصوت؟
It came from her room!
أتى من غرفتها
Matsumoto-sensei!
!سينسي! سينسي
It would seem that sodium hydroxide was mixed in with the lemon tea.
يبدو أنّ هيدروكسيد الصوديوم كان ممزوجاً مع الشاي بالليمون
So she drank it and then--
...شربته إذاً ثمّ
Huh? There's something floating in the lemon tea.
...ماذا؟ يوجد شيءٌ ما يطفو على الشاي بالليمون
It's a capsule!
!إنّها... كبسولة
What?!
ماذا؟
I see. So the perpetrator filled this capsule with sodium hydroxide,
فهمت، ملأ الفاعل هذه الكبسولة بهيدروكسيد الصوديوم
then slipped it into the lemon tea.
ثمّ وضعها في الشاي بالليمون
If so, then it would take time for the poison to be released,
عندها سيستغرق انتشار السمّ وقتاً
making it impossible to determine when the crime was committed.
مما يعسّر تحديد وقت ارتكاب الجريمة
In other words, any one of you six who entered her room
أي أنّ القاتل أحد الستّة الذين دخلوا غرفتها
could have poisoned the tea!
!يمكن لأيٍّ منكم تسميم الشاي
You can't be serious! Does that make me a suspect too?!
هل أنت جادّ؟! أأنا أحد المُشتبه بهم إذاً؟
Of course.
بالطبع
There are capsules that dissolve in hot water in only a few minutes' time.
توجد كبسولات تذوب في الماء الساخن ببضعة دقائق فقط
Okay! Have the capsule analyzed at once!
حسنٌ، اطلبوا تحليل الكبسولة فوراً
Say. How come you're not counting him?
ماذا عنه؟ لن تحسبه في القائمة؟
I'm pretty sure he entered the room too...
فقد دخل غرفتها بدوره
Come now, a police superintendent would never poison his own daughter.
أنت، لا يُعقل أن يُسمم مفوّض الشرطة ابنته
No, the boy's right. I'm a suspect just as much as the others.
كلا، معه حق. مُشتبه بي كما البقية
Y-You do have a point...
حـ-حسناً
Come to think of it, we were recording a video!
بالمناسبة، كنا نسجل تصويراً
What?!
!ماذا؟
You're right! Did we leave it on when we left?!
صحيح! أتركناها تعمل عندما غادرنا؟
The crime might've been caught on film!
!قد يكون المجرم ظاهراً في الفيلم
There you go!
هاك
You still drink this sugary rubbish...
...لا تزالين تشربين هذا الشراب السكّري
...That only I could ever make you happy.
وحدي من بإمكانه منحك السعادة
Are you still drinking this cheap filth?
لا تزالين تشربين هذا المشروب الرديء؟
It looks like the actual poisoning wasn't caught on tape.
يبدو أنّ التسميم المباشر لم يُسجّل
Though the video shows that nearly everyone touched the can at least once.
لكن أظهر الفيديو أنّ الجميع لمسوا العُلبة ولو مرّةً
Meaning that everyone had the chance to poison the drink.
أي أنّه كانت للجميع فرصة تسميم الشراب
They're still watching it...
...لا يزالون يشاهدونه
I wonder if Matsumoto-sensei's surgery is over...
هل انتهت عملية سينسي يا ترى؟
Poisoning her favorite lemon tea... how horrible!
يا للفظاعة، سمّموا الشاي بالليمون المفضّل لها
Lemon tea, huh...
...الشاي بالليمون
Every time Sayuri drinks it,
...كلّما شربته سايوري تعود لي
I'm reminded of a little girl I liked a lot a long time ago...
ذكريات الفتاة الصغيرة التي أحببتها في الماضي
She always drank it with such happiness,
كانت تشرب الشاي بالليمون الذي أعطيته إيّاها بسعادة دوماً
but I never even knew her name...
مع أنّه لم تسنح لي معرفة اسمها أبداً
Wait, he couldn't be...
...أيمكن أنّه
Inspector. The results of the analysis have come back.
حضرة المفتش، وصلت نتائج التحليل
First, assuming the capsule was added to the lemon tea,
،بدايةً، بافتراض أنّ الكبسولة أُضيفت للشاي بالليمون
it would apparently take 15 to 16 minutes for it to dissolve.
سيستغرق ذوبانها بين 15 إلى 16 دقيقة
15 to 16 minutes...
خمس عشرة إلى ستّ عشرة دقيقة؟
In other words, the poison was added
أي أنّ السم أُضيف قبل 15 دقيقة على الأقل
at least 15 minutes before she collapsed.
قبل أن تسقط العروس
It was 1:46 when Ran-kun called the police.
اتّصلت ران-كن بالنجدة عند 1:46
Assuming she collapsed to the floor one minute earlier,
،وبافتراض أنّها سقطت دقيقةً قبل ذلك
then that means the poison was added before 1:30.
أُضيف السم قبيل الواحدة والنصف
It was exactly 1:30 when Superintendent Matsumoto left.
كانت الساعة الواحدة والنصف عندما غادر المفوّض ماتسوموتو
What?!
!ماذا؟
Which rules out both the groom and myself.
أي أنّ هذا يبرّئني والعريس
We came to see Matsumoto-sensei after he did.
فقد أتينا لمقابلة سينسي بعده
We found something strange about the poisoned can...
هناك أمرٌ غريب في العلبة المسمومة
The superintendent's fingerprints aren't anywhere on it!
لم تحتو بصمات المفوّض
You fool! What are you talking about?!
!أحمق! ما الذي تقوله؟
As you can clearly see...
...كما ترون
...I had the can in my hand!
!أمسكتُ بالعلبة بيدي
Did you make a thorough check?
هل دققتم الفحص؟
Yes...
...أجل
That's strange...
...غريب
No way!
!مُحال
Really strange...
...غريبٌ حقاً
Wait a minute! When Sonoko left...
...لحظة، عندما غادرت سونوكو
...she didn't have her can with her!
!لم تحمل علبتها معها
Where in the world did it go?
أين هي يا ترى؟
What?!
!ماذا؟
Don't tell me that she drank from...
...أيمكن أنّ العلبة التي شربت منها
Say, mister. Were the superintendent's fingerprints the only ones missing?
أخبرني يا عمّ، أكانت بصمات المفوّض وحدها المفقودة؟
No, that Umemiya person's weren't on it either.
كلا، لم تكن بصمات أوميميا ذاك موجودة أيضاً
I figured as much!
كما ظننت
In that case, where did that capsule come from?
في تلك الحالة، من أين أتت تلك الكبسولة؟
That's it! I've figured out the culprit's intention!
!وجدتُها! اكتشفت نيّة المجرم
I know the truth behind that capsule!
!كما حقيقة تلك الكبسولة
Inspector. I found this in a trash can in the hallway.
حضرة المفتّش، وجدتُ هذه في سلّة قمامة في الرواق
A glass jar...
...قنّينة زجاجية
That looks like sodium hydroxide inside it.
يبدو أنّ هيدروكسيد الصوديوم بداخلها
Sodium hydroxide?!
هيدروكسيد الصوديوم؟
This could be the container the perpetrator used when poisoning the tea!
يمكن أن تكون الحاوية التي !استعملها المجرم عند تسميم الشاي
There's no doubt about it.
لا شكّ في الأمر
Sodium hydroxide is a dangerous chemical
هيدروكسيد الصوديوم مادةٌ كيميائية خطرة
that absorbs water in the air and turns into a liquid in mere minutes!
تمتصّ الماء في الهواء وتحوّله لسائل في بضعة دقائق
Okay. Send this for analysis too.
حسنٌ، أرسلها للتحليل أيضاً
I've figured it out!
حللتُها
It was that bastard who smeared her dress with blood!
كان ذاك الوغد هو من دنّس !فستان سينسي بالدماء
Inspector Megure!
المفتّش ميغوري
We want to see Matsumoto-sensei at the hospital right away!
نريد الذهاب لرؤية سينسي في المشفى فوراً
Hold on a little longer! We're not finished with our investigation!
!انتظرا قليلاً! لم ننه التحقيق بعد
Old man Mori isn't around today, so I'll need a pinch hitter!
،العمّ موري ليس موجوداً اليوم لذا أحتاج بديلَ طوارئ
Now to match this voice changer to Sonoko's voice...
حسنٌ، لأطابق مبدّل الصوت هذا ...بصوت سونوكو
Sonoko? What's the matter?
ما الخطب يا سونوكو؟
I figured out who poisoned Matsumoto-sensei's lemon tea.
ا-اكتشفتُ هوية من وضع السمّ في شاي ماتسوموتو سينسي بالليمون
You have, Sonoko-kun?!
!حـ-حقاً يا سونوكو-كن؟
You said that the perpetrator put the poison capsule in her tea
قلتم أنّ الفاعل وضع كبسولة السمّ في الشاي
15 minutes before she collapsed, right?
قبل 15 دقيقة من سقوطها، صحيح؟
Yes, because it would take 15 to 16 minutes for the capsule to dissolve.
أجل، لأنّ ذوبانها سيستغرق بين 15 و16 دقيقة
That's assuming the poison was really in that capsule.
هذا بافتراض أنّ السمّ كان حقاً في تلك الكبسولة
All we're sure of is that the capsule was floating in the poisoned lemon tea.
كلّ ما نحن على يقين منه الآن أنّ الكبسولة كانت تطفو في الشاي بالليمون المسموم
So you're saying that the culprit--
...أتقصدين أن المجرم
Yes. The poison and the capsule were added in separately
صحيح، أُضيف السمّ والكبسولة على حدة
to fool us into thinking that the poison was added at least 15 minutes prior.
لإيهامنا أنّ السم أُضيف قبل 15 دقيقة من سقوط سينسي
If that's true, then you two could have done it as well!
إن كان ذلك صحيحاً، فأنتما لستما مُستبعدين
Hold on. Everything she's saying is pure conjecture.
تمهل رجاءً، كلامها مجرد افتراضات
It really might have been a poison capsule.
قد تكون كبسولة سُم حقاً
No.
كلا
There is proof!
!هناك برهان... دليل
In the video that Ran taped.
في التسجيل الذي صوّرته ران
Inspector. Take a close look at the can of lemon tea on the screen.
حضرة المفتّش، أمعن النظر في علبة الشاي بالليمون على الشاشة
No way!
!مُحال
The labels are facing different directions!
!الشعار مقلوب
Ran. Do you remember where I put my lemon tea when this happened?
ران، أتذكرين أين وضعت علبة الشاي بالليمون خاصتي قبل مغادرتي؟
Yeah...
أجل
You were in a hurry so you put it on the table...
...كنتِ في عجلة فوضعتها على الطاولة
It couldn't be!
...أيمكن
Was that your can?!
كانت تلك علبتك؟
That's right.
صحيح
The reason it looks like there's only one can
سبب وجود صورة عُلبة واحدة
is because the two cans are perfectly lined up!
أن الاثنتين منتظمتان في صفّ واحد
She took my can, which just happened to be in front!
أخذَتْ علبتي التي صادف أنّها كانت في المقدمة
As proof of this,
،ودليلاً على ذلك
the poisoned can was devoid of the fingerprints of the superintendent
لم تكن بصمات المفوّض أو أوميميا-سان موجودةً
and Umemiya-san,
على العلبة المسمومة
even though they clearly had held the can earlier.
رغم أنّهما أمسكا بالعلبة بوضوح سابقاً
I'd bet that my fingerprints are on it, though.
توجد بصماتي عليها مع ذلك غالباً
She's exactly right!
إنّها محقة
Which means...
...مما يعني
...That some time between her taking the wrong can and collapsing,
في وقتٍ ما بين أخذ ابنتي ،للعلبة الخاطئة وسقوطها
someone put the poison and the capsule in separately.
أضاف أحدهم السم والكبسولة منفصلين
Yes. And the only ones with her at the time were Conan-kun
أجل، وكان كونان-كن بجوارها آنذاك
and Takasugi-san,
مع تاكاسوغي-سان
not to mention me and Ran.
كما أنا وران
Excluding Conan-kun,
باستثناء كونان-كن
when Ran and I returned from buying batteries,
عند عودتي وران من شراء البطارية
Takasugi-san was holding the can and then she took it from him,
،كان تاكاسوغي-سان يحمل العلبة
so it would've been impossible for me or Ran to poison it!
ثمّ أخذتها سينسي، فيستحيل عليّ وران تسميمها
So he's the only one left?!
أي هو الوحيد المتبقي؟
No. There's one other person.
كلا، يوجد شخصٌ آخر
Matsumoto-sensei, herself!
!إنّه سينسي نفسها
Suicide?!
أتقصدين انتحار؟
But if she did mix the poison in to kill herself,
،لكن إن أضافت السم للإقدام على الانتحار
she would've added it shortly before collapsing to the floor.
كانت لتضيفه قبيل سقوطها
And to do that, she would need two things.
وتحتاج شيئين لإتمام ذلك
An airtight container and a desiccant!
حاوية مكتومة ومُجفّف
It takes only a few minutes for sodium hydroxide to turn to liquid
يستغرق تحوّل هيدروكسيد الصوديوم لسائل بضعة دقائق فقط
when exposed to the air.
عند تعرّضه للهواء
She was in this room the entire time,
كانت في هذه الغرفة طوال الوقت
so she would have needed a container to safely store it in.
فكانت تحتاج حاويةً للاحتفاظ به بأمان
But the container was found...
...لكن عثرنا على الحاوية
...In a trash can in the hallway.
في سلّة مهملات في الرواق
Which is proof that someone other than Matsumoto-sensei
وهذا دليلٌ على أنّ شخصاً سوى سينسي
brought the poison into this room.
جلب السم لهذه الغرفة
In other words,
أي أن من كان
the only one who could've slipped the poison into the lemon tea...
...بإمكانه وضع السم في الشاي بالليمون
...was you, Takasugi-san!
!كان أنت يا تاكاسوغي-سان
Toshihiko! How could you?!
...توشيهيكو! أنت
Why? Why'd you do that to my daughter?!
!أخبرني! لمَ قمت بذلك لابنتي؟
If you wanna know so badly, then I'll tell you!
!سأخبرك إن كنت تريد المعرفة لذاك الحد
It all started 20 years ago!
بدأ الأمر قبل 20 عاماً
When a car that you were chasing ran over my mother!
!عندما دهستْ سيارةُ مجرم كنتَ تطارده أمّي
Mom! Mom!
!أمّي! أمّي
My mother was still alive at the time...
كانت أُمي لا تزال حيّةً آنذاك
She could've survived if you had rushed her to the hospital in your car!
كانت لتنجو لو نقلتَها للمشفى بسيّارتك فوراً
But instead...
...لكنّك
You're in the way! Get out of here!
!أنت تعترض طريقي! ابتعد
15 minutes later, my mother died, lying on the street.
بعدها بخمس عشرة دقيقة ماتت أمي على الطريق
From that day forth, I never once forgot your cruel, heartless face!
لم أنس وجهك القاسي عديم الرحمة !مُذ ذاك اليوم أبداً
Is he telling the truth, superintendent?
أهذه الحقيقة سيّدي المفوّض؟
Yes. I didn't see her--she was obscured by the car's shadow.
أجل، لم أرها. كانت ظلال السيّارة تحجبها
Later on, I learned of the accident and rushed to his house,
علمتُ بالحادثة لاحقاً وأسرعت لمنزله
but he had already moved out.
لكنه كان قد انتقل بالفعل
My mother was the only family I had.
كانت أُمي عائلتي الوحيدة
I was adopted by the Takasugi family as they had no children of their own.
تبنّتني عائلة تاكاسوغي التي لم تمتلك أبناءً
Then seven years ago, Kazumi brought a girl with her!
وقبل 7 أعوام، جلبت كازومي معها فتاةً في يومٍ لا ينمحي من ذاكرتي
Yes! The instant I learned that she was your daughter,
أجل، عندما أدركت أنّها كانت ابنتك
my nearly-forgotten flames of revenge roared back to life!
تأجّجت بداخلي نيران الانتقام التي كادت !تُنسى وأكلت أحشائي
Then why didn't you kill me?!
!لمَ لم تقتلني أنا إذاً؟
If you died, you wouldn't get to experience how heartbreaking it is
إن مت أنت فلن تشعر بعذاب ألم
to lose someone dear to you!
فقدان شخصٍ عزيز
She was one stupid girl, though!
لكنها كانت فتاةً غبيّة بحق
She had no clue I was getting close to her to get revenge!
لم تدرك أنّي اقتربتُ منها للانتقام
Though I'm sure being the heir to the Takasugi fortune was--
مع أنّ كوني وريث عائلة تاكاسوغي ...الثرية كان ما أغواها غالباً
You're the one who doesn't have a clue, Toshihiko!
!أنت الذي لم يدرك شيئاً يا توشيهيكو
Kazumi...
...كازومي
Sayuri knew everything!
كانت سايوري تعرف كلّ شيء
Even about the accident 20 years ago and your lineage!
!عن الحادثة قبل 20 عاماً كما أصل دمك
No, you're lying!
!كلا، تكذبين
She'd never marry me if she knew who I really was!
!لن تتزوّجني أبداً إن عرفت حقيقتي
You still don't get it, even after seeing all that lemon tea she drinks?!
لا تزال لا تفهم حتّى بعد رؤيتها تشرب الشاي بالليمون؟
You're the first boyfriend that she's always been thinking about
أنتَ المحبوب الأوّل الذي كانت تفكّر به سايوري دوماً
for the past 20 years!
!للعشرين عاماً الفائتة
Sayuri kept talking about how much you looked like him,
كانت سايوري تتكلم عن شبهك به باستمرار
so I did some investigating and found out.
فتحرّيتُ في الأمر وعرفت الحقيقة
She was really worried, even after she accepted your proposal...
كانت قلقةً جداً حتى بعد قبولها تقدّمك للزواج
She didn't know what to do to earn your forgiveness...
لم تعرف كيف تكسب غفرانك
Even so, you went and...
...ومع ذلك قمتَ بـ... قمتَ بكلّ شناعة
Don't tell me she saw him poison the drink?!
أيمكن أنّها رأته يُسمم الشراب؟
She knew it was poisoned?!
عرفتْ أنّه مسموم؟
Don't worry, I'll be there soon!
لا تقلق، سألحق بك قريباً
Matsumoto-sensei...
...سينسي
Superintendent! We just received word from the hospital!
!سيّدي المفوّض! وصلتنا رسالة من المشفى
She's been upgraded to stable condition!
!استقرّت حالة الآنسة بعد العملية
This is great!
!مرحى
Hurray!
!حمداً لله
Two months later, Matsumoto-sensei checked out of the hospital.
خرجت سينسي من المشفى بعد شهرين
It's great that you got to leave the hospital earlier than expected!
من الرائع أنّك غادرتِ المشفى قبل الوقت المتوقع
And I hear that Toshihiko-san's sentence was reduced...
كما سمعت أن حُكم توشيهيكو-سان قد خُفّف
Well, I did drink the poison of my own free will...
كنتُ من شرب السمّ بإرادتي
But in the end, it looks like I only succeeded in getting him in trouble...
لكن في النهاية، يبدو أنّي ألحقت المتاعب به فقط
I bet he hates me now...
يكرهني الآن حتماً
Cheer up!
!ابتهجي يا سينسي
In celebration of leaving the hospital, I'll buy a drink for you!
!سأشتري عصيراً لك احتفالاً بخروجك
Really?!
حقاً؟
In that case...
...إذاً سأختار
...lemon tea, it is!
!الشاي بالليمون، لا غيره
It's important to cherish memories of the past!
!من المهم الاعتزاز بذكريات الماضي
Really now! If you keep this up, you'll never get married!
يا إلهي، لن تتزوّجي أبداً إن واصلتِ البقاء هكذا
But she was married three years later...
لكنّها تزوجت بعد 3 أعوام
Married to the one she had thought about for 20 long years, of course.
ومن نفس الشخص الذي عاش في أفكارها لعشرين عاماً بالطبع
Nothing of the sort!
!أبداً
There's no way you could possibly be the murderer!
!يستحيل أن تكوني المجرمة
Why not?
لمَ يستحيل ذلك؟
You were the one who just explained why she couldn't have done it!
أنتَ من وضّح أن ليس بإمكانها !أن تكون الفاعلة
That's it! Now I get it!
!هكذا إذاً، فهمت
This is an alibi trick involving elevators!
!إنّها حيلة حجّة غياب باستعمال المصعد
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Elevator Murder Case.
جريمة قتل المصعد
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Bouquet.
باقة أزهار